VISHAL ASOKAN

Design Engineer

E-Mail : vishalasokan1@gmail.com

Mobile : +91 8667553301 / +91 8438480949

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/vishal-asokan-5b9516113

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

An Engineering professional with more than three years of experience providing technical direction on designing of special purpose machine and process equipment. Meticulous creation of 3D Models, 2D drafting, layout, Jigs and fixtures apart from maintaining documents as per the ISO standards.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Milindia Pvt. Ltd.

March 2019–Till Now

Milindia are India's leading source for service to the soap, detergent, and fatty acid and glycerin industries. Milindia's strength lies on manufacturing and supply of special purpose machines used in pharmaceutical and food processing industries.

Designation: Junior Design Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Managed all phases of the design process for a multitude of products, components, parts, assemblies and subassemblies, including drafting, dimensioning, tolerance, prototyping and documenting results.
- Designed innovative component/module replacements for existing machinery that improved functioning and extended the life of soap finishing line equipment thought to be obsolete for a fraction of the total replacement cost.
- Compilation of BOM in ERP, gained diverse mechanical design experience sheet metal/welded assembly design, tubing/hose/fitting design, corrosion control, ferrous and aluminum casting design, bearing system/gear design, pneumatic controls.
- Design Documentation preparing & maintaining such as Design Issue Control Record, Design Change Record and Design Deviation report.
- Creation of 3D/CGI and graphic composition using keyshot.

ISF Industries Pvt. Ltd.

April 2018 – January 2019

ISF has emerged as a total solution provider, and have demonstrated the ability to design and manufacture of wide range of processing machinery and equipment to International Standards, such as dairy plants and food processing plants.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for Part Modeling/surface modeling the automation machine components such that it satisfies the aesthetic quality and manufacturing easiness.
- Sheet Metal designing which includes covers, frame cladding sheets and new product development as per the requirements for the machine.
- Assigned with the responsibilities of creating the Dimensional drawings (Drafting), Main Assembly drawing, Part Drawings.
- Responsible for preparing complete Bill of Materials (BOM) as per the requirements from Planning, Manufacturing & Assembly departments.
- Laser Cutting / Water jet cutting drawings Layout and nesting preparation.
- Costing & Estimation of the designed machine so as to plan whether the design is successful and meets the company's necessity, failing leads to re-design.
- Analysis using DFMEA of the process equipment.
- Developing Piping layout according to site plant for process machineries.
- Developing of equipment like BMC, HTST Pasteurizers, Storage tanks, CIP Tanks etc..

M/S Sreevatsa Stainless Steel Fabricators Pvt. Ltd.

July 2016 – April 2018

One of leading Designers and Fabricators of Steel / Stainless steel Sterilizers, Micron filters, Interior railings, Modular kitchens, Storage tanks, Food counters etc...

Responsibilities:

- Member of New Product Development Team.
- Preparation of all In-process drawing with GD & T parameters for the NPD components.
- Responsible for Prototype development, Reverse engineering related to NPD development.
- Developing Jigs & Fixtures as per estimated cost for NPD projects.
- Developing 3D models, assembly procedure and 2D drafting using Solidworks and AutoCAD.

SOFTWARE AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Having sound knowledge in following design software
 - o Solidedge
 - Solidworks
 - o AutoCAD
 - keyshot
 - Plant Design Management System
- Comprehensive knowledge in engineering GD&T.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of Engineering

B.E. Mechanical 6.59 CGPA Dhaanish Ahmed College of Engineering

2012-2016

Senior Schooling

12th Grade 77.83% Zion Matriculation Higher Secondary School

2012

Junior schooling

10th Grade 7.2 CGPA Kendriya Vidyalaya No2 (afs) Tambaram

2010

PERSONAL DOSSIER

Father's Name : Late Asokan K.K.

Mother's Name : Rama G.

Date of Birth : 23 April 1995 (24 years)

Sex : Male

Address : 35, 2nd main road, Sri Sathya Sai Nagar, Rajakilpakkam, Tambaram, Chennai-600073

Languages Know: English, Tamil, Hindi, and Malayalam

Document Supporting the Above details can be furnished if required. The above details are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Delhi-NCR Vishal Asokan